<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN" 
	"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" [
		<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../Common/xinclude.mod">
		%xinclude;
]>

<section id="conventions">
	<title>Conventions</title>
	<para>
		<emphasis role="bold">Admonishments</emphasis>
	</para>
	
	<note>
		<para>Notes are used to provide additional information to supplement or provide details related to the topic being discussed.</para>
	</note>
	<tip>
		<para>Tips are used to suggest easier or alternate ways of accomplishing a goal.</para>
	</tip>
	<caution>
		<para>Cautions are used to ward readers away from potential problems or difficulties.</para>
	</caution>
	<warning>
		<para>Warnings are used to prevent readers from making changes which could be difficult, if not impossible, to reverse.</para>
	</warning>

	<para>
		<emphasis role="bold">References</emphasis>
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>References to other sections will look like <quote><link linkend="conventions">Conventions</link></quote>.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>References to remote resources will look like <quote><ulink url="http://www.python.org">Python.org</ulink></quote>.</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	
	<para>
		<emphasis role="bold">Typographic conventions</emphasis>
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>Filenames and paths will use <filename>monospace</filename> type.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Commands to be entered at prompts will use <emphasis role="bold">bold</emphasis> type.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Elements to be clicked or selected in a user interface will use <emphasis role="bold">bold</emphasis> type.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>When variables or parameters are contained within a paragraph, they will use <filename>monospace</filename> type.</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	
	<para>
		<emphasis role="bold">Navigation</emphasis>
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>Menu sequences will be displayed as follows:</para>
			<para><emphasis role="underline">F</emphasis>ile -> <emphasis role="underline">O</emphasis>pen</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Mouse actions shall assume a right-handed mouse configuration.</para>
			<para>The terms <quote>click</quote> and <quote>double-click</quote> refer to using the left mouse button.</para>
			<para>The term <quote>right-click</quote> refers to using the right mouse button.</para>
			<para>The term <quote>middle-click</quote> refers to using the middle mouse button, pressing down on the scroll wheel, or pressing both the left and right buttons simultaneously, depending on available features of the mouse used.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Keyboard short-cut combinations will be displayed as follows:</para>
				<para>Ctrl+N</para>
				<para>Where the conventions for the <quote>Control</quote>, <quote>Shift</quote>, and <quote>Alternate</quote> keys will be Ctrl, Shift, and Alt, respectively, and shall mean the first key is to be held down while pressing the second key.</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	
	<para>
		<emphasis role="bold">Code conventions</emphasis>
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>Code and mark-up samples will be presented as follows:</para>
			<programlisting>
<![CDATA[
import os
import sys
import types
import shutil
from xml.dom import Node
from xml.dom.ext.reader.Sax import FromXmlFile

#This manages plugins and handles the execution of events.
import control.plugin
#This is a general-purpose module for asynching functions that aren't part of an
# independent thread.
import control.asynch
#This manages connections and plugin events.
import ircAbstract.ircInterface
]]>
			</programlisting>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Sometimes, lines of code or mark-up examples will be longer than the page width.
			To avoid having them run off the page, the slash character, <quote>\</quote>, will be used to denote a soft line break.
			This means that the code is, in reality, meant to be on one line, but for print formatting, it has been split across two or more lines.</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	
	<note>
		<para>Unless otherwise noted, a *nix operating environment will be assumed, and standard Xorg functions will be referenced.
		Users of other operating systems are assumed to be familiar with their environment and able to interpret commands and paths to achieve the same results on their platforms.</para>
	</note>
</section>
