<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" [
		<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../Common/xinclude.mod"> %xinclude;
]>

<chapter id="dict-evt-except">
	<title>Event Dictionary Exceptions</title>
	<para>
		This section contains a listing of all Event Dictionaries that are not
		quite so simply sent to and from the IAL.
	</para>
	
	<section id="eevt-emit-generic">
		<indexterm type="dict-except">
			<primary>Dictionaries - Exceptions</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<title>Emit Generic</title>
		<para>
			This dictionary is used to capture unrecognized commands the user
			enters at a UI. It should only be sent to the IAL by UIs and
			plugins that gather input directly from the user.
		</para>
		<para>
			If untouched, this event will be seen by each plugin, but not the
			UI, once before	it is converted into a
			<link linkend="evt-in-irc-raw-command">IRC Raw Command</link>
			dictionary and sent to the IRC server. If your plugin knows what to
			do with the user's command, it should process it and either return
			None if other plugins should be given a chance to evaluate its
			contents, or return	a
			<link linkend="eevt-raise-event">Raise Event</link> dictionary to
			alter the processing flow.
			<literallayout>
	See also:
	- <link linkend="eevt-emit-known">Emit Known</link>
	- <link linkend="eevt-raise-event">Raise Event</link>
			</literallayout>
			<programlisting>
<![CDATA[{
 'eventname': "Emit Generic",
 'irccontext': <:int>,
 'target': <:unicode>,
 'message': <:unicode>
}

eventname:
	The IAL-recognized name of this event.
irccontext:
	The session-unique ID of the connection to which this event should be sent.
target:
	The location to which the event should be sent, if it is context-sensitive.
message:
	The string this event was generated to convey.]]>
			</programlisting>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="eevt-emit-known">
		<indexterm type="dict-except">
			<primary>Dictionaries - Exceptions</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<title>Emit Known</title>
		<para>
			This dictionary is used to capture recognized commands the user
			enters at a UI. It should only be sent to the IAL by UIs and plugins
			that gather input directly from the user.
		</para>
		<para>
			This dictionary will never actually be sent to any plugins. Instead,
			it will be unwrapped, and the dictionary it contains will be made
			accessible. This dictionary's sole purpose is to control the flow of
			processing.
			<literallayout>
	See also:
	- <link linkend="eevt-emit-generic">Emit Generic</link>
			</literallayout>
			<programlisting>
<![CDATA[{
 'eventname': "Emit Known",
 'eventdict': <:dict>
}

eventname:
	The IAL-recognized name of this event.
eventdict:
	The known dictionary that is wrapped by this event.]]>
			</programlisting>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="eevt-raise-event">
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Dictionaries - Exceptions</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<title>Raise Event</title>
		<para>
			This dictionary is not actually sent to or from the IAL. Instead, it
			is returned when another dictionary is received if a plugin needs to
			change the flow or subject of processing.
		</para>
		<para>
			Raise Event dictionaries may be used to change the
			<link linkend="dict-inbound">Inbound Event Dictionary</link> being
			processed, to prevent a dictionary from being seen by any more
			plugins, or to end processing altogether.
			<programlisting>
<![CDATA[{
 'eventname': "Raise Event",
 'behaviour': <"replace"|"skiprest"|"skipall">
 'eventdict': <:dict|None>
}

eventname:
	The IAL-recognized name of this event.
behaviour:
	This parameter must be one of three strings.
	"replace":
		Continue processing along the normal flow.
		Replace the dictionary being processed with the one in 'eventdict'.
	"skiprest":
		Skip all remaining plugins in the processing flow.
		If 'eventdict' is specified, it will replace the current dictionary.
	"skipall":
		End processing.
		'eventdict' is not used.
eventdict:
	A spec-compliant Inbound Event Dictionary, or None if the current dictionary
	should not be replaced.]]>
			</programlisting>
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
