<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" [
		<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../Common/xinclude.mod"> %xinclude;
]>

<chapter id="dict-info">
	<title>Information Dictionaries</title>
	<para>
		This section contains a listing of all Information Dictionaries used to
		provide commonly required information. These dictionaries are generally
		received as part of Outbound Event Dictionaries.
	</para>

	<section id="inf-channel-data">
		<indexterm type="dict-information">
			<primary>Dictionaries - Information</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<title>Channel Data</title>
		<para>
			This dictionary contains all known information about a channel on an
			IRC server, including a list of all its users.
			<literallayout>
	See also:
	- <link linkend="req-irc-get-channel">IRC Get Channel</link>
			</literallayout>
			<programlisting>
<![CDATA[{
 'channel': <:unicode>,
 'topic': <:unicode|None>,
 'modes': <:tuple>,
 'modestring': <:unicode>,
 'modestringsafe': <:unicode>,
 'users': <:dict>
}

channel:
	The name of the channel being described.
topic:
	The current topic of the channel, or None if no topic has been set.
modes:
	A tuple containing all modes currently set in the channel.
	Its elements may be single-character mode tokens, or tuples containing a
	mode token and a parameter token.
modestring:
	A string that represents all modes currently set in the channel.
modestringsafe:
	A string that represents all modes currently set in the channel, minus
	those that contain sensitive information, like passwords.
users:
	A dictionary of ]]><link linkend="inf-user-data">User Data</link><![CDATA[ information dictionaries,
	keyed by lowercase username.]]>
			</programlisting>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="inf-server-data">
		<indexterm type="dict-information">
			<primary>Dictionaries - Information</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<title>Server Data</title>
		<para>
			This dictionary contains all known information about an IRC server.
			<literallayout>
	See also:
	- <link linkend="req-irc-get-server">IRC Get Server</link>
			</literallayout>
			<programlisting>
<![CDATA[{
 'irccontext': <:int>,
 'networkname': <:unicode|None>,
 'groupname': <:unicode|None>,
 'username': <:unicode>,
 'ident': <:unicode|None>,
 'realname': <:unicode|None>,
 'address': <:unicode|None>,
 'port': <:int|None>,
 'localip': <:unicode>,
 'lastaction': <:float>,
 'modes': <:tuple>,
 'modestring': <:unicode>,
 'channels': <:dict>
}

irccontext:
	The session-unique identifier of the server.
networkname:
	The name of the IRC network to which the server belongs, if connected.
groupname:
	The user-specified name of the network group, used to provide consistency to
	plugins. May be None if the server is not part of a named group.
username:
	The nickname used by PyRC.
ident:
	The ident used by PyRC, if a connection has been attempted.
realname:
	The real name used by PyRC, if a connection has been attempted.
address:
	The address of the IRC server, if connected.
port:
	The port of the IRC server, if connected.
localip:
	The IP address associated with PyRC.
lastaction:
	The number of seconds that have elapsed since the user last acted on the IRC
	server via PyRC.
modes: 
	A tuple of modes applied to PyRC by the IRC network.
	Its elements may be single-character mode tokens or tuples containing a
	single-character mode token and a single-token parameter.
modestring:
	A string that represents every mode currently set on PyRC.
channels:
	A dictionary of ]]><link linkend="inf-channel-data">Channel Data</link><![CDATA[ information dictionaries,
	keyed by lowercase channel names.]]>
			</programlisting>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="inf-user-data">
		<indexterm type="dict-information">
			<primary>Dictionaries - Information</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<title>User Data</title>
		<para>
			This dictionary contains all known information about a user on an
			IRC server, optionally including channel-specific data.
			<literallayout>
	See also:
	- <link linkend="req-irc-get-user">IRC Get User</link>
			</literallayout>
			<programlisting>
<![CDATA[{
 'username': <:unicode>,
 'ident': <:unicode|None>,
 'hostmask': <:unicode|None>,
 'realname': <:unicode|None>,
 'country': <:unicode>,
 'ircserver': <:unicode|None>,
 'lastactionglobal': <:float|None>,
 'lastactionchannel': <:float|None>,
 'symbol': <:unicode|None>
}

username:
	The nickname of the user being described.
ident:
	The ident of the user, if known.
hostmask:
	The hostmask of the user, if known.
realname:
	The real name supplied by the user, if known.
country:
	The user's country, based on a TLD lookup.
ircserver:
	The URL of the IRC server to which the user is connected, if known.
lastactionglobal:
	The time at which the user last performed an action anywhere, if known.
	Expressed as a UNIX timestamp.
lastactionchannel:
	The time at which the user last performed an action in a channel, if known.
	Expressed as a UNIX timestamp.
	
	This field will never be filled in non-channel-specific contexts.
symbol:
	The dominant rank symbol attached to the user, if any.
	If not None, its length is always one character.
	
	This field will never be filled in non-channel-specific contexts.]]>
			</programlisting>
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
